{"id":"2018_15","name":"","memoryVerse":"\"The Lord your God will certainly make a lasting dynasty for my lord, because you fight the Lord's battles, and no wrongdoing will be found in you as long as you live.\" â€“ 1 Samuel 25:28b","dayQuestions":{"one":{"title":"FIRST DAY: Read the notes and the references.","questions":[{"id":"2018_15_1","questionText":"1. Use this space to record how you have seen God's activity during the week. (How has He provided, answered, comforted, reconciled, guided, etc.?)","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_15_2","questionText":"2. What from the notes, lecture, group sharing or personal study impacted you most in the past week?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"two":{"title":"SECOND DAY: Read 1 Samuel 28.\nSaul secretly consulted a medium for help.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"28:1-999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_15_3","questionText":"3. What fears might David and Saul had about the battle? How did their fears influence their behavior?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_15_4","questionText":"4. What is wrong with consulting a medium? How do you respond when a friend or superior asks you to participate in an unethical situation? (See Leviticus 19:31 and 1 Chronicles 10:13-14.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Leviticus","verse":"19:31"},{"book":"1 Chronicles","verse":"10:13-14"}]},{"id":"2018_15_5","questionText":"5. Where do you turn when it seems the Lord is silent or not telling you want you want to hear?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"three":{"title":"THIRD DAY: Read 1 Samuel 29.\nDavid was released from fighting against Israel.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"29:1-999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_15_6","questionText":"6. What conflict arose between Achish and his men?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_15_7","questionText":"7. How do you see God at work in David's situation?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_15_8","questionText":"8. How have you seen God's protection in your own life?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"four":{"title":"FOURTH DAY: Read 1 Samuel 30 with Psalm 36.\nDavid and his men defeated the Amalekites and shared the plunder.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"30:1-999"},{"book":"Psalm","verse":"36:1-999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_15_9","questionText":"9. Describe the scene at Ziklag. How did David and his men respond?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_15_10","questionText":"10. What leadership qualities do you see in David? Which ones will you ask the Lord to develop in you?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_15_11","questionText":"11. How does Psalm 36 encourage you?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Psalm","verse":"36:1-999"}]}]},"five":{"title":"FIFTH DAY: Read 1 Samuel 31 with 1 Chronicles 10.\nSaul took his own life.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"31:1-999"},{"book":"1 Chronicles","verse":"10:1-999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_15_12","questionText":"12. Describe the events surrounding Saul's death. Who took care of the bodies of Saul and his sons? (See 1 Samuel 11:1-11.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"11:1-11"}]},{"id":"2018_15_13","questionText":"13. How might God be calling you to go out of your way to do something honorable or compassionate?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_15_14","questionText":"14. What was the summation of Saul's life? What do you hope will be said of you in relation to the Lord at the end of your life? (See 1 Chronicles 10:13-14.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"1 Chronicles","verse":"10:13-14"}]}]},"six":{"title":"SIXTH DAY: Review 1 Samuel 28-31 with 1 Chronicles 10, and Psalm 36.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"28:1-31:999"},{"book":"1 Chronicles","verse":"10:1-999"},{"book":"Psalm","verse":"36:1-999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_15_15","questionText":"15. How did this week's study impact your thinking about the necessity to seek and trust God's guidance rather than looking to the world for wisdom?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]}}}